Sanjeev Rawal

Asst. Manager (JavaScript Developer)
Hindustan Petroleum Corporation Limited
B.Tech, Indian Institute of Technology Ropar

Email Id: Sanjeevery@gmail.com, +91 8396010999

Summary:

Total 8 years' experience. 4 Years' experience as Sales Manager (Direct Sales) in leading Oil & Gas Company. 4 Years' experience as Operations Manager (Oil Terminal). Skilled in HTML, CSS, JavaScript. Looking for role as IT Project Manager/Frontend Developer/JavaScript Developer.

Work Experience: -

Hindustan Petroleum Corporation Limited (2015 to present):

Asst. Sales Manager-Industrial & Consumer Products (April 2021 to present)

- ➤ Gave profit of Rs 30.1 Cr to HPCL in Direct Sales in FY 2022-23 and gave profit of Rs 24.5 Cr in FY 21-22.
- ➤ Handling major industrial clients. Meeting with Clients. Negotiations on prices. Convincing clients to purchase from HPCL.

Sales Officer - Industrial & Consumer Products (June 2020 to April 2021)

Contributed profit of Rs 22 Cr in FY 2020-21.

Operations Officer - Supply Chain management (Sept 2015 to June 2020)

- ➤ Single handedly managed petroleum depot of 9,390,000 litres petroleum (explosive) products.
- > Successfully managed a team of 28 workforce and trained them to work safely and effectively with petroleum products.

Education:

- > Secured All India Rank 3305 in IIT JEE 2010. Secured All India Rank 792 in GATE 2015.
- ➤ Indian Institute of Technology Ropar, Punjab B.Tech in Mechanical Engineering CGPA:7.81 / 10

(July 2010 - May 2014)

Projects:

1.) Weather Forecast Web App:

Description: Created a weather forecast web application that utilizes APIs like OpenWeatherMap to provide real-time weather data for various locations. The project demonstrates my proficiency in data fetching and displaying dynamic information.

Skills Demonstrated: JavaScript, API Integration, Front-End Development, Responsive Design.

2.) Interactive Game with HTML5 Canvas:

Description: Developed an interactive browser-based game using HTML5 Canvas and JavaScript. This project demonstrates my ability to create engaging and interactive web experiences.

Skills Demonstrated: HTML5 Canvas, JavaScript Game Development, Front-End Development.

.....

Additional Skills and Extracurricular activities:

- Client Handling and client meetings
- Negotiation and client convincing skills.
- Management and sales skills
- HTML
- CSS
- Bootstrap
- JavaScript
- DOM
- React.JS Library for frontend Development
- MySQL language for managing database.
- GitHub
- Redux.JS
- Data Structure and Algorithms
- Ex NCC Cadet.
- Good presentation skills.
- Leadership

Certifications:

➤ "Achieving Excellence in Sales Leadership: A 360 degree approach" from <u>IIM Amritsar</u> in 2021. 40 Week Course.

➤ "Management Development for Young Officers" from <u>IIM Indore</u> in 2017.